#### **Yannick Beaucaine**

+61 450 420 313

yannick.beaucaine@gmail.com

### **Personal Summary**

I have an extensive background in the hospitality industry with 20 years of experience where I have worked in a myriad of roles but more specifically, as a Multi-site Operations Manager. As an Operations Manager, I have managed up to 4 venues including cafes, hotels, bars and restaurants. I have worked in a variety of settings that range from casual and fine dining to Michelin Star restaurants. I have been responsible for the management and mentoring of venue managers, head chefs, general assistants and leaders with attention to the allocation of their duties and specific tasks. I have provided strong leadership and management to my team and work collaboratively with all team members to ensure successful and profitable implementation.

I have a strong attention to detail and I am committed to excellence in quality service, with a strong understanding of financial control and KPI's. I have extensive knowledge in hygiene control, ensuring that we are implementing and maintaining all protocols of HACCP. I am proactive and take action to minimise wastage at all stages. I have well developed communication skills and can speak four languages fluently (French, Portuguese, Spanish and English). In addition, a key component of my role as an Operations Manager is customer service: liaising and building relationships with suppliers to negotiate the best prices of products for the business as well as building a loyal customer base. Furthermore, my management roles have involved administration tasks such as the preparation of the weekly rosters to ensure adequate coverage to meet service requirements and the recruitment, training, supervision and mentoring of staff of all levels.

### Qualifications

Professional Bachelor of Hospitality Management Superior Hospitality School of Paris (Ceproc), France	2001 - 2003
Certificate of Qualification of Culinary Arts Belliard Hospitality School of Paris, France	1998 – 2001
Professional Patent's Studies of Culinary Arts Belliard Hospitality School of Paris, France	1998 – 2001

# **Employment Experience**

Production Kitchen Su	pervisor
-----------------------	----------

Made Establishment /Comida foods (FMCG Production/ Food Production)

**Group Operations Manager** 

The Grocer Co./STELLER, Melbourne

Glamorama Group, Melbourne

(Continental Hotel, AMPM, The Groundskeeper, The Grocer Co.)

**Operations Manager** 

(Glamorama Bar, Less Then Zero, A Girl Called Jane)

**Head Chef** 

**F&B Operations Manager** 

Speakeasy Kitchen Bar

December 2018 - Present

October 2017 - December 2018

November 2015 - June 2017

September 2012 – October 2014

August 2010 - January 2012

Centre Helio Marin/Atlantic Club, Montalivet France

## **Executive Chef**

Centre Helio Marin/Atlantic Club, Montalivet France

February 2008 – August 2010

## Other

- ➤ Victorian Responsible Service of Alcohol
- Victorian Drivers Licence ( Motorbike )
- Professional Diploma in Photography
- ➤ Advanced knowledge in computers and POS Systems
- > Extensive knowledge with Microsoft Office Software Suite

## References

available upon request